<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.1"
          urlbase="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/"
          
          maintainer="webmaster@eclipse.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>214158</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-02 16:31:00 -0500</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Data Visualization Customization - Customized CMDBf Response</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-01-03 13:54:25 -0500</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Eclipse Foundation</classification>
          <product>z_Archived</product>
          <component>Cosmos</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>ASSIGNED</bug_status>
          <resolution></resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://wiki.eclipse.org/COSMOS_Design_214158</bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard>new_tooling</status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          <blocked>211093</blocked>
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Sheldon Lee-Loy">sleeloy</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Jimmy Mohsin">jim</assigned_to>
          <cc>sleeloy</cc>
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124547</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Sheldon Lee-Loy">sleeloy</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-02 16:31:46 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>A programming strategy is needed to associate a customized view with a particular graph response.  
A graph response is a generic structure that represents data from a data manager.  Customized data is wrapped inside a graph response that application may want to provided customized view to visualize the data.  

Lets consider some different types of customized views.

1.  Creating graph data.  The graph can be a pie chart, line chart, bar chart, etc. Determine which 
chart type to use can be business-user specific not data driven.
2.  Show the data in the tree
3.  Show the data in a table
4.  Complex widget that is composed of many simple widgets

The following are some design issues:

1.  How can a customized view be associated with a graph response?
2.  Should the ui customization be data driven or application driven.   


Application-Driven Customization
=================================
Tradionally, the application developer determines the view that will render the data.  For example, if a 
cmdbf query is constructured to return statistical data for a particular web server the application developer
may decide to render the statistical data as a line chart.  In other cases, the application developer may
want to render the data as a table depending on the application context.  

In this case, a registry service is need to associate a view with a graph query instead of the graph 
response.  Note that the view expects a certain graph response format that is dictated by the graph 
query.

The above mechanism requires a datafeed that accepts a graph query id and returns a graph response that
tags the response with the graph query id.  The graph query id will be used to lookup the registered
view assoicated with the graph query.

Data-Driven Customization
=========================
In this case the data recieved from a CMDBf graph response will determine the view to render the graph response.
Does data driven customization useful?  Need to understand uses cases that would make this useful.

In this case, a registry service is need to associate a view with a graph response instead of a graph query</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1328287</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Sheldon Lee-Loy">sleeloy</who>
    <bug_when>2008-09-10 09:28:28 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Changing owner to martin as he is the DV lead.</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>