<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.1"
          urlbase="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/"
          
          maintainer="webmaster@eclipse.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>214157</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-02 16:24:00 -0500</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Add bundle for rome</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-02-13 16:53:28 -0500</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>4</classification_id>
          <classification>Tools</classification>
          <product>Orbit</product>
          <component>bundles</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>PC</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Linux</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          <blocked>214159</blocked>
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Steffen Pingel">steffen.pingel</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Chris Aniszczyk">caniszczyk</assigned_to>
          <cc>caniszczyk</cc>
    
    <cc>jeffmcaffer</cc>
    
    <cc>mik.kersten</cc>
    
    <cc>nitind</cc>
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124535</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Steffen Pingel">steffen.pingel</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-02 16:24:04 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>The ROME library provides a set of tools for parsing, generating and publishing RSS and Atom feeds:

 https://rome.dev.java.net/
 
Version 0.8 has been approved for the Mylyn project. It would be great if there was an Orbit bundle for it.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124599</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Chris Aniszczyk">caniszczyk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-02 17:41:29 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Is there an IPZilla request for Orbit yet? If not, I can do one.

Do you prefer 0.9 as that&apos;s the latest?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124620</commentid>
    <comment_count>2</comment_count>
    <who name="Eugene Kuleshov">ekuleshov</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-02 18:03:24 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>ROME is used by Mylyn web connector. 0.8 seem to work ok there. If 0.9 won&apos;t add big overhead to the IP process, it would be nice to update.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124621</commentid>
    <comment_count>3</comment_count>
    <who name="Chris Aniszczyk">caniszczyk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-02 18:08:17 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>ok, version bumps should be quick.

I created CQ:
https://dev.eclipse.org/ipzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=1943</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124628</commentid>
    <comment_count>4</comment_count>
    <who name="Steffen Pingel">steffen.pingel</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-02 18:16:13 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Thanks a lot Chris! I&apos;ll make sure to file the CQ beforehand next time.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124650</commentid>
    <comment_count>5</comment_count>
    <who name="Jeff McAffer">jeffmcaffer</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-02 20:21:22 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>You (mylyn guys) need to enter a CQ for use of this lib in mylyn regardless of whether or not it is in orbit (or any other project for that matter).  

Is there someone in the Mylyn community volunteering to do the bundling in Orbit (or contribute the bundled libs)?  Orbit itself is not staffed by a group of people able to bundle for others.  It is a place for sharing work that would normally be done by your project.  that is, the work should be done by you as it would normally be done but shared through orbit so others can share and we can ship a release in June that has some coherence.  If you can convince someone else (e.g., Chris) to do this for you, great.  Otherwise someone from the consuming projects needs to step up.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124677</commentid>
    <comment_count>6</comment_count>
    <who name="Mik Kersten">mik.kersten</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-02 21:07:16 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Thanks for the CQ Chris and thanks for the explanation Jeff.  Fyi, we are tracking Orbit priorities on bug 214159. My comment on the CQ regarding ROME 0.9 was the following:

&quot;Currently this is low priority for the Mylyn project because Rome is only used for a Mylyn Sanbox (i.e. Incubation) component.  I&apos;ll hold off on entering the new CQ [for ROME 0.9] until we have our full prioritized list of Ganymede CQs.&quot;

Eugene: Note that if we make a Mylyn Incubator project (bug 214182) we will be able to get ROME 0.9 via the Parallel IP process.  Is there any bug fix or new feature that we require from ROME 0.9?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124691</commentid>
    <comment_count>7</comment_count>
    <who name="Steffen Pingel">steffen.pingel</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-02 21:32:59 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>I apologize for filing this bug prematurely without having a sufficient understanding of the Orbit process. I will be happy to create the Orbit bundles when the CQ is approved.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124713</commentid>
    <comment_count>8</comment_count>
    <who name="Eugene Kuleshov">ekuleshov</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-02 22:03:13 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Mik, no bugs that I know of require ROME 0.9. Also, in my recollection, Mylyn&apos;s web connector is not a sandbox thing in a sense Eclipse projects use it. That component been available for quite while with the main tool, unless of course your intention is to demote it to sandbox.

Jeff, I wouldn&apos;t mind to maintain ROME on Orbit if that would help</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1124784</commentid>
    <comment_count>9</comment_count>
    <who name="Mik Kersten">mik.kersten</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-03 01:42:59 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext> (In reply to comment #8)
&gt; Mik, no bugs that I know of require ROME 0.9. Also, in my recollection, Mylyn&apos;s
&gt; web connector is not a sandbox thing in a sense Eclipse projects use it. That
&gt; component been available for quite while with the main tool, unless of course
&gt; your intention is to demote it to sandbox.

Sorry, I was being vague about something we have not yet established, i.e. which Mylyn components belong in the Incubator project.  All projects that are on the regular download site need to stay in the base project, but for each of the &quot;extras&quot; and &quot;experimental&quot; projects we can decide on the best home (e.g. if one would benefit more from experimentation).  We should continue that discussion more on bug 214182.
 
&gt; Jeff, I wouldn&apos;t mind to maintain ROME on Orbit if that would help

Eugene, if you would like to take this on please assign this bug to yourself and proceed with Rome 0.8.  As far as I know only Mylyn&apos;s web connector currently has interest in Rome, but it is possible that other projects find the bundle useful.  Also, as discussed on our other Orbit bugs it would be great to move our dependencies to Orbit asap.  Note that the Mylyn build process will require significant update before we can consume the bundle, but that&apos;s already on Rob&apos;s plate.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1125237</commentid>
    <comment_count>10</comment_count>
    <who name="Eugene Kuleshov">ekuleshov</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-03 15:17:22 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to comment #9)
&gt; &gt; Jeff, I wouldn&apos;t mind to maintain ROME on Orbit if that would help
&gt; 
&gt; Eugene, if you would like to take this on please assign this bug to yourself and
&gt; proceed with Rome 0.8.  As far as I know only Mylyn&apos;s web connector currently
&gt; has interest in Rome, but it is possible that other projects find the bundle
&gt; useful.  Also, as discussed on our other Orbit bugs it would be great to move
&gt; our dependencies to Orbit asap.  Note that the Mylyn build process will require
&gt; significant update before we can consume the bundle, but that&apos;s already on Rob&apos;s
&gt; plate.

I am not sure how the administrative process for contributing components to Orbit works. Can someone give me any pointers?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1125240</commentid>
    <comment_count>11</comment_count>
    <who name="Christian W. Damus">give.a.damus</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-03 15:24:48 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Have you reviewed the relevant Wiki pages?

http://wiki.eclipse.org/Orbit

(in particular, links &quot;Bundle Naming&quot;, &quot;Adding Bundles to Orbit&quot;, and &quot;Source Bundles&quot;)</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1125354</commentid>
    <comment_count>12</comment_count>
    <who name="Eugene Kuleshov">ekuleshov</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-03 17:24:36 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Christian, yes I did read trough the wiki which describe technical details. My question was about the administrative part of the process, given that I am not a committer on the Orbit project.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1125422</commentid>
    <comment_count>13</comment_count>
    <who name="Jeff McAffer">jeffmcaffer</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-03 22:09:36 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>For the most part this is covered in
   http://wiki.eclipse.org/Orbit_Faq#How_do_I_become_a_committer_in_Orbit
You simply agree that you are going to manage/maintain some of the bundles in Orbit and we initiate a vote stating that commitment.  In general we have tried to have a small number of Orbit committers per Eclipse project to remain focussed and ensure that bundles get created in a consistent way etc.  I don&apos;t know if Mylyn already has an Orbit committer.  This is not a rule, just a general practice.

So if you want to maintain some bundles that are already approved then follow the FAQ and state your intentions in a mailing list post...</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1125476</commentid>
    <comment_count>14</comment_count>
    <who name="Mik Kersten">mik.kersten</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-04 01:41:11 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Mylyn does not yet have an Orbit committer.  I have added an item to our next weekly meeting so that committers can discuss how best to proceed with the tasks of creating the bundles and and updating our build process.

http://wiki.eclipse.org/Mylyn/Meetings#Tuesday.2C_January_9.2C_10-11am_PT</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1155978</commentid>
    <comment_count>15</comment_count>
    <who name="Mik Kersten">mik.kersten</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-13 10:40:40 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Steffen: Mylyn is now approved for Rome 0.9.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1155983</commentid>
    <comment_count>16</comment_count>
    <who name="Chris Aniszczyk">caniszczyk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-13 10:45:23 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Mylyn needs to file a CQ for reuse of the bundle from Orbit. I&apos;m going to commit rome to Orbit later today.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1156029</commentid>
    <comment_count>17</comment_count>
    <who name="Chris Aniszczyk">caniszczyk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-13 11:28:27 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Mylyn guys, Rome requires JDom? Correct? How do you deal with this dependency within Mylyn?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1156144</commentid>
    <comment_count>18</comment_count>
    <who name="Eugene Kuleshov">ekuleshov</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-13 13:07:49 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Chris, jdom been approved for Mylyn in CQ 2051. Currently that jar is bundled in org.eclipse.mylyn.web.core along with rome jar.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1156207</commentid>
    <comment_count>19</comment_count>
    <who name="Chris Aniszczyk">caniszczyk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-13 14:08:17 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>ok, Rome should appear in Orbit builds &gt;20080213

I added JDOM as a dependency which is already in Orbit.

Let me know if this works for you or if you have any issues consuming Rome.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1156228</commentid>
    <comment_count>20</comment_count>
    <who name="Steffen Pingel">steffen.pingel</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-13 14:20:31 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Wow! That was quick.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1156373</commentid>
    <comment_count>21</comment_count>
    <who name="Mik Kersten">mik.kersten</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-13 16:53:28 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Thanks Chris!</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>