<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.1"
          urlbase="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/"
          
          maintainer="webmaster@eclipse.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>214277</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-03 16:39:00 -0500</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Enhance the screenshot page</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2012-09-10 21:38:00 -0400</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Eclipse Foundation</classification>
          <product>Community</product>
          <component>Website</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>PC</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows XP</op_sys>
          <bug_status>ASSIGNED</bug_status>
          <resolution></resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc>http://www.eclipse.org/screenshots/</bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords>helpwanted</keywords>
          <priority>P4</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          <dependson>359754</dependson>
    
    <dependson>363524</dependson>
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Chris Aniszczyk">caniszczyk</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Denis Roy">denis.roy</assigned_to>
          <cc>benjamin</cc>
    
    <cc>davymeers</cc>
    
    <cc>Ed.Merks</cc>
    
    <cc>jeffmcaffer</cc>
    
    <cc>torkildr</cc>
    
    <cc>wayne</cc>
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1125311</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Chris Aniszczyk">caniszczyk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-03 16:39:30 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>The current screenshots page is kind of lame (http://www.eclipse.org/screenshots/). It would be nice if it featured screenshots of Eclipse say running on devices (ie., eRCP), web browsers (a la RAP) and cool RCP applications (ie., Lotus Notes, RSSOwl, etc...)

When I usually visit something, the first thing I do is look for screenshots and it would be nice if this was enhanced since it&apos;s linked so prominently from the main page.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1125331</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Wayne Beaton">wayne</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-03 17:02:23 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>If you can provide me with some less lame screenshots, I&apos;ll update the page.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1125339</commentid>
    <comment_count>2</comment_count>
    <who name="Chris Aniszczyk">caniszczyk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-03 17:09:36 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>I will try to come up with something :P

It&apos;s not that lame, but things have changed :)

Maybe a public call will help!</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1940074</commentid>
    <comment_count>3</comment_count>
    <who name="Denis Roy">denis.roy</who>
    <bug_when>2011-05-27 16:53:07 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>This page is absolutely horrible...  I will do something about it.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1940143</commentid>
    <comment_count>4</comment_count>
    <who name="Wayne Beaton">wayne</who>
    <bug_when>2011-05-27 19:24:19 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Anything we do here needs to be sustainable. It&apos;d be nice if we could get the projects to maintain this. As much as I&apos;d rather not add to the portal, how about we add a new screenshot metadata entry that we can mine to populate the page?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1940784</commentid>
    <comment_count>5</comment_count>
    <who name="Denis Roy">denis.roy</who>
    <bug_when>2011-05-30 10:13:01 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>&gt; Anything we do here needs to be sustainable.

I disagree.  If we take that approach, we&apos;ll never get it done.  Even if we do a one-off update, at least our screenshots page will look modern for a couple of years, to the benefit of everyone.

Regardless, my intention was to move the screenshots page to the Wiki, so that everyone can (easily) contribute to the coolness without pushing even more overhead onto the projects themselves.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1940838</commentid>
    <comment_count>6</comment_count>
    <who name="Wayne Beaton">wayne</who>
    <bug_when>2011-05-30 11:18:08 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to comment #5)
&gt; &gt; Anything we do here needs to be sustainable.
&gt; 
&gt; I disagree.  If we take that approach, we&apos;ll never get it done.  Even if we do
&gt; a one-off update, at least our screenshots page will look modern for a couple
&gt; of years, to the benefit of everyone.
&gt; 
&gt; Regardless, my intention was to move the screenshots page to the Wiki, so that
&gt; everyone can (easily) contribute to the coolness without pushing even more
&gt; overhead onto the projects themselves.

So you&apos;re saying that we should move it to the wiki to make it more (sus|main)tainable?

+1</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>2004168</commentid>
    <comment_count>7</comment_count>
    <who name="Wayne Beaton">wayne</who>
    <bug_when>2011-10-03 13:55:53 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>I&apos;d like to see this moved to the Wiki.

But... it doesn&apos;t seem like we have much traction.

AFAICT, there are no links anywhere to the page itself.

There is a function in /home/scripts/functions.php named randomScreenshot that, AFAICT, is not used. 

I recommend that we just kill /screenshots for now. If something becomes real in the Wiki, we can connect that something with a redirect later.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>2015743</commentid>
    <comment_count>8</comment_count>
    <who name="Torkild U. Resheim">torkildr</who>
    <bug_when>2011-10-24 16:24:35 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>This is maybe a bit far fetched, but I&apos;ll have a go anyway: What if each project information page had some feature where one could add one or more screenshots which would be collected and presented on the screenshots page? E.g. add screenshots to http://www.eclipse.org/projects/project.php?id=eclipse.orion, show them in the project and screenshots page with descriptions and the latter with links to the Orion project.

I guess most people already using some feature of Eclipse don&apos;t really care whether or not there is a main screenshots page, however it would still be interesting to see screenshots from new/unknown projects. And I think potential users of Eclipse will find all screenshots interesting.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>2015751</commentid>
    <comment_count>9</comment_count>
    <who name="Davy Meers">davymeers</who>
    <bug_when>2011-10-24 16:31:29 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Personally i never noticed that page but if you decide to keep it then IMHO it
would have to serve like a showcase of the possibilities of eclipse.

Some random idea&apos;s:

- use some kind of image gallery script (like for example
http://www.jcarousel.com/) to present the photo&apos;s.
- make sure the page has the same design as http://www.eclipse.org/
- show other pictures depending on the OS the visitor is using (but still give
the ability to look at screenshots from another platform)


I would expect screenshots off all the packages i can download directly from
http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/. Also, i would expect screenshots of the
parts that make eclipse stand out.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>2084608</commentid>
    <comment_count>10</comment_count>
    <who name="Wayne Beaton">wayne</who>
    <bug_when>2012-03-22 12:55:42 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Here&apos;s what I&apos;m thinking...

Building a screenshots page is not all that hard. Maintaining it (i.e. keeping it up-to-date) is the hard part.

As part of the new Project Management Infrastructure (Bug 363868) we&apos;re providing a means of consistently capturing information about individual project releases. I propose that we extend this implementation to associate a handful of screenshots with a release.

With that information in place, we can generate a script that pulls screenshots from the latest releases of each project.

Any project that wants their project represented on a &quot;screenshots&quot; page need only ensure the screenshots associated with their most current release be up-to-date. They can even specify screenshots for future releases that will automatically be adopted when a future release becomes the current release.

There&apos;s a little more discussion of this on Bug 363524</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>2085192</commentid>
    <comment_count>11</comment_count>
    <who name="Denis Roy">denis.roy</who>
    <bug_when>2012-03-23 14:06:56 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>&gt; Any project that wants their project represented on a &quot;screenshots&quot; page need
&gt; only ensure the screenshots associated with their most current release be
&gt; up-to-date.

Sounds like the best idea so far.</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>