<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.1"
          urlbase="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/"
          
          maintainer="webmaster@eclipse.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>214412</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-04 17:52:00 -0500</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Create an independent feature for ICU4J plug-in</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2009-07-09 14:14:14 -0400</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Eclipse</classification>
          <product>Platform</product>
          <component>Releng</component>
          <version>3.4</version>
          <rep_platform>PC</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows XP</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Yoshito Umaoka">yoshito_umaoka</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Platform-Releng-Inbox">platform-releng-inbox</assigned_to>
          <cc>kim.moir</cc>
    
    <cc>Tod_Creasey</cc>
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1126125</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Yoshito Umaoka">yoshito_umaoka</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-04 17:52:10 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Build ID: 3.4

Steps To Reproduce:
ICU4J plug-in is currently a part of org.eclipse.rcp feature.  ICU team often provides data updates for time zone rule, which were distributed via the Eclipse software update site as feature patches.  Each patch is supposed to work with any maintenance releases within a same Eclipse feature code stream.  But, each of them requires corresponding RCP feature ID.  For example, Eclipse 3.3 includes ICU4J plug-in 3.6.1.  A same patch works well for ICU4J plug-in included in Eclipse 3.3/3.3.1/3.3.1.1.  But the patch must have the exact target feature ID, thus, it requires 3 different installable patch features including the same contents for them.  In general, fixes in ICU4J plug-in is independent from RCP feature.  For now, we (ICU team)only provides tzdata updates, but we may want to release other type of patches in future.  This bug report proposes to separate ICU from RCP feature in Eclipse 3.4 and beyond, so it makes us (ICU team) to maintain the ICU plug-ins independent from RCP releases.

More information:</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1127327</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Kim Moir">kim.moir</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-08 10:45:01 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>So what you are requesting is a separate feature that only contains the icu bundle?  Th rcp feature would include this new feature? My understanding is that the new provisionig work that should be included in the SDK in in M5 should make a lot of this pain go away.  In any case, having another feature below rcp will require pmc approval.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1549009</commentid>
    <comment_count>2</comment_count>
    <who name="Kim Moir">kim.moir</who>
    <bug_when>2009-07-09 14:14:14 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Closing. I don&apos;t think that we&apos;ll be implementing this change.</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>