<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.1"
          urlbase="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/"
          
          maintainer="webmaster@eclipse.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>214698</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-08 19:05:00 -0500</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>[Component-Proposal] MIGLayout support in SWT</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2009-11-24 06:18:52 -0500</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>5</classification_id>
          <classification>Technology</classification>
          <product>Nebula</product>
          <component>Core</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>PC</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Kai Schlamp">schlamp</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</assigned_to>
          <cc>andre.dietisheim</cc>
    
    <cc>bokowski</cc>
    
    <cc>caniszczyk</cc>
    
    <cc>christian.gesswagner</cc>
    
    <cc>christian.scheja</cc>
    
    <cc>codex69</cc>
    
    <cc>djo</cc>
    
    <cc>djspiewak</cc>
    
    <cc>eclipse</cc>
    
    <cc>eclipse</cc>
    
    <cc>elias</cc>
    
    <cc>fonolit</cc>
    
    <cc>fyaoxy</cc>
    
    <cc>jason.henriksen.spam</cc>
    
    <cc>junk</cc>
    
    <cc>max.gilead</cc>
    
    <cc>qualidafial</cc>
    
    <cc>remysuen</cc>
    
    <cc>spacehorst</cc>
    
    <cc>stefan.loetscher</cc>
    
    <cc>steve_northover</cc>
    
    <cc>tom.schindl</cc>
    
    <cc>will.horn</cc>
          
          <votes>54</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1127826</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Kai Schlamp">schlamp</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-08 19:05:24 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>With the current layout managers, that are provided by SWT, some things are really  unhandy to code. Unhandy in the sense of generating bloated code.
The situation intensifies as there is no good GUI builder available for Eclipse Europe.
On the other side, there is currently a top 25 enhancement request at Sun to include MigLayout (the Swing part only) to JDK 7.
As MigLayout (www.miglayout.com) also supports SWT it would be nice to have it in SWT as well. MigLayout is under the BSD license.
If you don&apos;t know it, then please give it a try, or look at a little example (picture + code) I set up on my page (http://www.medicalgenomics.org/miglayout_sample).
As you&apos;ll see, the code is good readable and comparatively short.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1128440</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Mikael Grev">junk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-09 15:48:50 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>There is even a file called called IDEUtil that is made for IDE interaction in the distribution. It can be used to parse and output the constraints needed, both as strings and chainable API calls. This should make IDE integration a snap.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1180111</commentid>
    <comment_count>2</comment_count>
    <who name="Xiang Qinxian">fyaoxy</who>
    <bug_when>2008-03-19 10:29:35 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to comment #1)
&gt; There is even a file called called IDEUtil that is made for IDE interaction in
&gt; the distribution. It can be used to parse and output the constraints needed,
&gt; both as strings and chainable API calls. This should make IDE integration a
&gt; snap.
&gt; 

+1.
Mikael, You should commit it must before:)
Month Ago, I wanted to mail you for the vote. OK, you do.
Greate work!!</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1205518</commentid>
    <comment_count>3</comment_count>
    <who name="jason henriksen">jason.henriksen.spam</who>
    <bug_when>2008-04-16 18:20:31 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>I&apos;m using MigLayout in two production projects.  I&apos;d love it if I didn&apos;t have to explain what it was and why I&apos;m using it any more.  I&apos;m willing to help with test/coding/documentation if help is needed.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1247067</commentid>
    <comment_count>4</comment_count>
    <who name="Daniel Spiewak">djspiewak</who>
    <bug_when>2008-05-24 21:48:53 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>+1

I usually lean against integration of third-party stuff into SWT.  However, in this particular case, I would be in favor of it.  MiGLayout is absolutely tremendous, and could even be the basis for a far more powerful VE plugin.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1270972</commentid>
    <comment_count>5</comment_count>
    <who name="Max Gilead">max.gilead</who>
    <bug_when>2008-06-14 07:29:36 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>+1 BUT, wouldn&apos;t it be preferable to replace text-based configuration with a class? Even in Kai&apos;s simple example you&apos;d need to remember format and keywords for:

&quot;[right]10[left, grow]&quot;
&quot;growx, wrap&quot;
&quot;width 100!, split&quot;
&quot;gapleft 10, wrap&quot;

Not to mention that some of that is rather cryptic (e.g. what does exclamation mark means? Negation? Fixed size? If so, what kind of size it is without it?). I know I can read documentation, I&apos;m just trying to tell that it&apos;s not obvious.

To make it more compact it could be a chained operation, e.g.

label.setLayoutData(new MIGLayoutData().setLeftGap(10).setWrap());

This way compiler can check at least for syntax validity of such configuration statement (and we all like when we know about errors sooner than later, don&apos;t we? :))
</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1270975</commentid>
    <comment_count>6</comment_count>
    <who name="Mikael Grev">junk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-06-14 07:35:02 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Max,

Thank you for your support.

Luckily I have already added exactly that type of API you are looking for. Look in the Swing demo at the last two examples.

You can write code that looks like:

new MigLayout(new LC().fill().wrap().width(&quot;200&quot;));

Same type of API works for column/row and component constraints.

Cheers,
Mikael</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1270978</commentid>
    <comment_count>7</comment_count>
    <who name="Stefan Lötscher">stefan.loetscher</who>
    <bug_when>2008-06-14 08:03:30 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to comment #5)
I like the textual configuration. With this feature it is very simple to create dynamic UI&apos;s where the configuration of the components can be loaded from the server side as an example.

Cheers,

Stephan

</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1289651</commentid>
    <comment_count>8</comment_count>
    <who name="John Matthews">marshal_davout</who>
    <bug_when>2008-07-11 13:31:42 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Excellent add-on to Java.  This is the one layout manager that should replace all the other Java layout Managers.  I have saved so much time with using Miglayout, I highly recommend it to all Java developers.  Now if we can just get an IDE that creates Java GUI&apos;s that work better than Jigloo or JFormDesigner, and use Miglayout my headaches would almost be gone.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1291398</commentid>
    <comment_count>9</comment_count>
    <who name="Mikael Grev">junk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-07-15 08:58:49 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>I wonder, why has this RFE been take off of the main page suddenly?

https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1385813</commentid>
    <comment_count>10</comment_count>
    <who name="Max Gilead">max.gilead</who>
    <bug_when>2008-12-07 18:38:53 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Any news on this RFE? I joked on IRC today that I&apos;ll probably join the Church of MigLayout ;) But seriously, this is excellent layout and recently I started to use it for basically everything because of its flexibility and minimal amount of configuration needed to get the job done. Can we expect it to be integrated into SWT anytime soon?

And I second Mikael&apos;s question: why this bug is not on main bugzilla page? With 39 votes it should be #1 RFE (current #1 RFE which is bug #241476 has only 14 votes).</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1385819</commentid>
    <comment_count>11</comment_count>
    <who name="Will Horn">will.horn</who>
    <bug_when>2008-12-07 18:59:57 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>&gt; And I second Mikael&apos;s question: why this bug is not on main bugzilla page? With
&gt; 39 votes it should be #1 RFE (current #1 RFE which is bug #241476 has only 14
&gt; votes).

I think this is because Eclipse moved this to the Nebula project where unofficial enhancements to SWT live.  MigLayout is a great layout manager, but I doubt it will ever become part of official SWT (as much as we all wish it was!).
</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1385829</commentid>
    <comment_count>12</comment_count>
    <who name="Boris Bokowski">bokowski</who>
    <bug_when>2008-12-07 19:14:54 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>I cannot speak for the SWT or Nebula teams, but shouldn&apos;t this bug have an attachment with the source code of MiGLayout, together with a statement from the author that he is contributing this to Eclipse, and willing to change its license to the EPL (or dual-license it under EPL and something else)?

Without this, it cannot even be considered for inclusion in Nebula, which would be the appropriate place for it in the Eclipse project structure.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1385883</commentid>
    <comment_count>13</comment_count>
    <who name="Mikael Grev">junk</who>
    <bug_when>2008-12-08 00:57:42 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Hello,

The source code is available from www.miglayout.com. It is also in the main Maven depo.

I am definitely willing to dual license it under EPL (as well as BSD).

Cheers,
Mikael</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1386021</commentid>
    <comment_count>14</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2008-12-08 05:41:56 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Hi Mikael,

Nebula is currently changing it&apos;s internal structure (every widget will eventually get a subproject on its own) and maybe we need to move out of technology and find another place for Nebula (Platform would be a natural choice IMHO) because we can&apos;t do 1.0 releases inside Technology. Boris do you think this makes sense?

I&apos;ll try to write a draft proposal Nebula-Component-Contributors can use to propose their Component to Nebula/Eclipse. I&apos;m taking ownership of this bug and ping you as soon as I have the draft but I&apos;d also invite you to subscribe to nebula-dev-mailing list.

Tom Nebula-Co-Project-Lead</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1386161</commentid>
    <comment_count>15</comment_count>
    <who name="Boris Bokowski">bokowski</who>
    <bug_when>2008-12-08 09:35:07 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to comment #14)
&gt; Nebula is currently changing it&apos;s internal structure (every widget will
&gt; eventually get a subproject on its own) and maybe we need to move out of
&gt; technology and find another place for Nebula (Platform would be a natural
&gt; choice IMHO) because we can&apos;t do 1.0 releases inside Technology. Boris do you
&gt; think this makes sense?

This makes a lot of sense to me. Do you know if a project in incubation can have subprojects that are no longer incubating?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1386203</commentid>
    <comment_count>16</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2008-12-08 10:02:34 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Boris one can&apos;t do a 1.0 release while in incubation. This is why we are splitting Nebula into subproject then every sub-project on itsown can decide whether they are in incubation, doing a release (only a project can do a release which would mean nowadays that Nebula only can do a 1.0, 1.0.1, ... which will never happen). 

I&apos;m just working on a little RCP-Application which should support contributors creating (Nebula-)Component-Proposal =&gt; Creating the Review Documents, ... .</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1451674</commentid>
    <comment_count>17</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2009-03-13 05:13:51 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>There is a high interest to bring this Widget to Eclipse and I&apos;m accepting contributions. 

The problem I&apos;m seeing in moving the code to Nebula is that MigLayout is not only for SWT but also for Swing and I myself already thought about porting it to QT(Jambi). So there&apos;s a mismatch between Nebula and this contribution. 

I&apos;m not sure where an appropriate place for such a layout would be. The only place currently dealing with multi widget toolkit support is UFaceKit [1] which supports various widget technologies from SWT over Swing to QT(Jambi) and we are already using Mig-Layout in our internal implementations.

Any other ideas?

Another thing I&apos;m not sure about is whether it is possible to dual license code coming from Eclipse.

[1]http://wiki.eclipse.org/UFaceKit</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1451677</commentid>
    <comment_count>18</comment_count>
    <who name="Mikael Grev">junk</who>
    <bug_when>2009-03-13 05:21:07 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Hello Tom,

Just to be clear, MigLayout supports both Swing and SWT (and JavaFX) but this is through different code bases. There is a separate .jar for the different widget frameworks. So, I think that you should maybe only include the SWT part. About 90% of the code if common for all ports of course, but that shouldn&apos;t mean that the SWT version is &quot;polluted&quot; by Swing and JavaFX and vice versa.

When it comes to licensing I am very flexible and can release MigLayout under any license you want. I am very pragmatic and just want this layout manager to be used as much as possible.

Porting it to Qt sounds very interesting. Let me now if you need something from me to make this easier.

Cheers,
Mikael</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1451694</commentid>
    <comment_count>19</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2009-03-13 05:43:05 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Hi Mikael,

Do I get this right you don&apos;t have a common base but when fixing a problem in the common stuff you fix it twice (once in the SWT-Code base and once in the Swing-Code base).

Could you please provide me with a link to your source-code-repository to check out the code and take a look.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1451727</commentid>
    <comment_count>20</comment_count>
    <who name="Mikael Grev">junk</who>
    <bug_when>2009-03-13 06:36:08 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Tom,

I don&apos;t have to fix it twice furtunately. Internally I have all sources (except the JavaFX port which is hosted by Dean Iverson) in one repo. But the SWT and Swing specific code is held in different packages. The common package, which is the layout engine (the 90%), is totally widget platform independent. So if you want a pure SWT version is very easy to get.

The two packages you want is:

net.miginfocom.layout.*  (no widget references, just two proxy interfaces)
net.miginfocom.swt.*     (three SWT impl. classes)

I have the SVN repo on an internal server ATM. Since I guess you&apos;ll be hosting this in some other repo would it be OK if you just got the source from the source.jar?

If you are going to add MigLayout I guess we should discuss how to formalize the process for when I fix a bug in it so that you can get that change in a good and orderly way.

Cheers,
Mikael</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1618628</commentid>
    <comment_count>21</comment_count>
    <who name="Christian Gesswagner">christian.gesswagner</who>
    <bug_when>2009-10-29 06:52:43 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>it is just too good to ignore it. for the nebula project it will be an enrichment.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1618982</commentid>
    <comment_count>22</comment_count>
    <who name="Matthew Hall">qualidafial</who>
    <bug_when>2009-10-29 13:06:43 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Mikael, the approval process cannot proceed any further without a source code attachment.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1619467</commentid>
    <comment_count>23</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2009-10-30 04:07:59 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Another strategy I thought about is bringing an OSGi Bundle into the orbit</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1619959</commentid>
    <comment_count>24</comment_count>
    <who name="Mikael Grev">junk</who>
    <bug_when>2009-10-30 18:53:31 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Hello guys,

I did try to OSGi-enable my Mave build script without success.

I can attache the sources, no problem, but is that enough? I mean the sources is in a Maven repo, isn&apos;t it better to pull them from there since then you&apos;ll get updates? I don&apos;t know anything about the Eclipse world unfortunately so you&apos;ll have to tell me what&apos;s the most efficient way forward.

Cheers,
Mikael</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1623403</commentid>
    <comment_count>25</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2009-11-05 15:28:03 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>I can only get approval for released version and once you release the next one I can reapprove it, ... .

But I found the source code (3.7.1) on your page and will file a CQ to get it into orbit in a few minutes.

I&apos;ll keep you updated about the progress.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1623417</commentid>
    <comment_count>26</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2009-11-05 15:51:01 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>I filed a CQ waiting for a Orbit bug and CQ so that MigLayout can be imported into Orbit and delivered as an OSGI-Bundle from there.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1625005</commentid>
    <comment_count>27</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2009-11-09 17:47:30 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Ok. We got ultra fast IP-Approval (thanks to Eclipse IP-Team and Mikael for his fast responses) - we are now trying to bring this into Orbit and I&apos;ll keep you updated.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1631069</commentid>
    <comment_count>28</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2009-11-19 13:50:54 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>MigLayout is not part of Orbit and can consumed from there. Not sure what to do with this bug. If nobody speaks up in the next days, I&apos;m going to close it as WONTFIX because bringing MiGLayout-Sources to nebula is not needed.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1631078</commentid>
    <comment_count>29</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2009-11-19 14:02:58 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to comment #28)
&gt; MigLayout is not part of Orbit and can consumed from there. Not sure what to do

Should be: 
----------
MigLayout is *now* part of Orbit and can consumed from there. Not sure what to do</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1631235</commentid>
    <comment_count>30</comment_count>
    <who name="Endre Stølsvik">eclipse</who>
    <bug_when>2009-11-19 18:47:42 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Isn&apos;t WONTFIX a rather strange resolution when one is effectively talking about FIXED?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1633026</commentid>
    <comment_count>31</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2009-11-24 04:24:01 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to comment #30)
&gt; Isn&apos;t WONTFIX a rather strange resolution when one is effectively talking about
&gt; FIXED?

From a nebula-dev PoV it is a WONTFIX because we are not going to host this component in our repo. The first dev builds are ready http://download.eclipse.org/tools/orbit/committers/drops/I20091124014054/ but I haven&apos;t tested them yet.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1633033</commentid>
    <comment_count>32</comment_count>
    <who name="Endre Stølsvik">eclipse</who>
    <bug_when>2009-11-24 04:38:43 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Maybe &quot;quit&quot; this bug with a reference to a corresponding bug in the other place?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1633037</commentid>
    <comment_count>33</comment_count>
    <who name="Thomas Schindl">tom.schindl</who>
    <bug_when>2009-11-24 04:46:21 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to comment #32)
&gt; Maybe &quot;quit&quot; this bug with a reference to a corresponding bug in the other
&gt; place?

Here we go. The MiGLayout has been brought into Orbit as of bug #295507.</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>