<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.1"
          urlbase="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/"
          
          maintainer="webmaster@eclipse.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>214699</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-08 19:21:00 -0500</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Change &quot;awaiting committer&quot; notification emails to go to only the people listed on the ipzilla, not to the project mailing list</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-04-28 18:06:08 -0400</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>1</classification_id>
          <classification>Eclipse Foundation</classification>
          <product>Community</product>
          <component>IPZilla</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>All</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>All</op_sys>
          <bug_status>CLOSED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>P1</priority>
          <bug_severity>major</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Bjorn Freeman-Benson">bjorn.freeman-benson</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Gabe O&apos;Brien">gabe.obrien</assigned_to>
          <cc>barb.cochrane</cc>
    
    <cc>bokowski</cc>
    
    <cc>carolynmacleod4</cc>
    
    <cc>gabe.obrien</cc>
    
    <cc>janet.campbell</cc>
    
    <cc>sharon.corbett</cc>
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1127834</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Bjorn Freeman-Benson">bjorn.freeman-benson</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-08 19:21:09 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>As Caroyln says:
Bjorn - the only people who care at all about a specific IPzilla contribution are the people who are explicitly listed in the contribution report.

In the specific case of the report that I was notified about: https://dev.eclipse.org/ipzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=1876
the only people who should have received a notification email are:

Genie Eclipse &lt;genie@eclipse.org&gt;
Sharon Corbett &lt;sharon.corbett@eclipse.org&gt;

Boris_Bokowski@ca.ibm.com;
emo-ip-team@eclipse.org;
janet.campbell@eclipse.org;
Karice_McIntyre@ca.ibm.com;
sharon.corbett@eclipse.org;
Tod_Creasey@ca.ibm.com

Do you agree?</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1127835</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Bjorn Freeman-Benson">bjorn.freeman-benson</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-08 19:21:34 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>P1 so that this is fixed ASAP before the next round of reminder emails.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1127836</commentid>
    <comment_count>2</comment_count>
    <who name="Bjorn Freeman-Benson">bjorn.freeman-benson</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-08 19:23:26 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Actually, let&apos;s revise the rule a little: send the first three weeks of notifications just to the list of people and then, if it&apos;s still waiting with no action taken, perhaps the people are no longer with the project? In which case, send the rest of the notifications to the project mailing list.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1127838</commentid>
    <comment_count>3</comment_count>
    <who name="Gab&amp;eacute;">gabe</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-08 19:35:13 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>So should I change all of the four different email types to this new scheme?

The people to email is not available in the portal I will have to query IPZILLA for it.  

Should we turn on these emails until I can get this new scheme worked out?

Or should we just use the nag feature of bugzilla (I think someone mentioned it had this feature)?

gO&apos;</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1128732</commentid>
    <comment_count>4</comment_count>
    <who name="Gabe O&apos;Brien">gabe.obrien</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-10 03:05:14 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>I talked with Bjorn on the phone and he had me change both the &apos;awaiting_project&apos; and &apos;awating_committer&apos; to mail the bug and not the project memebers or mailing list.  Emails will be sent to the reporter, assinged_to and CCed.  

I still have to implement the switch after 3 weeks.  Should be done by the end of this week.

gO&apos; </thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1129292</commentid>
    <comment_count>5</comment_count>
    <who name="Janet Campbell">janet.campbell</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-10 16:28:43 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>With the Portal implementation, the PMC does not appear to be automatically copied on the IPbug.  How is the PMC initially being made aware of the contribution now?  Also, if they are not copied on the IPBug initially, they will not be &quot;reminded&quot; if we use the approach of reminding the &quot;CC&quot; list.  

Separately, while I think there is value in adding a notation on the bug that there has been a reminder, there is no need for the IPTeam to receive email notification.  Is there a way to turn email notification off for the IPTeam for this kind of notice?

Thanks,
Janet</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1129306</commentid>
    <comment_count>6</comment_count>
    <who name="Gab&amp;eacute;">gabe</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-10 16:42:37 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Should the PMC be email for all the four different email reminders:

  awaiting_committer 
  new (with no attached code)
  awaiting_project
  awaiting_pmc

Of course the PMC is already email for the awaiting_pmc.

Also, I am working on a way for a comments to show up in on a IPZILLA bug without having to email anyone.

gO&apos;
</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1129359</commentid>
    <comment_count>7</comment_count>
    <who name="Bjorn Freeman-Benson">bjorn.freeman-benson</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-10 18:06:40 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>(In reply to comment #5)
&gt; With the Portal implementation, the PMC does not appear to be automatically
&gt; copied on the IPbug.  How is the PMC initially being made aware of the
&gt; contribution now?  Also, if they are not copied on the IPBug initially, they
&gt; will not be &quot;reminded&quot; if we use the approach of reminding the &quot;CC&quot; list.  

Correct - the PMC is currently not notified of new IPbugs nor will they be notified of the &quot;awaiting_committer&quot; state using the CC list mechanism. I&apos;m going to argue that the PMC does not need to be notified of the &quot;awaiting_committer&quot; state (feel free to counter-argue).  As for the initial notification of the PMC - should they be notified? If so, we (you) should open a new bug about that and we&apos;ll add a mechanism for them to be notified.
</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1130826</commentid>
    <comment_count>8</comment_count>
    <who name="Janet Campbell">janet.campbell</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-14 12:55:00 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>We should ensure that reminder notifications are not sent out in instances where the bug has been &quot;resolved&quot;.

Janet</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1131110</commentid>
    <comment_count>9</comment_count>
    <who name="Gabe O&apos;Brien">gabe.obrien</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-14 19:50:36 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>I fixed the emails so they only show bugs that are NOT marked as  &apos;CLOSED&apos; or &apos;RESOLVED&apos;.  We didn&apos;t send out more emails than we should have.  But the emails that did get sent out had WAY more bugs listed than should have.

Sorry about that.  Karl is releasing this to the portal as I type this entry, so it will be fixed going forward.

gO&apos;</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1132701</commentid>
    <comment_count>10</comment_count>
    <who name="Gabe O&apos;Brien">gabe.obrien</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-16 15:50:14 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>I committed code that blocks sending emails to emo-ip-team@eclipse.org and anyone who is on the IP team (according to the foundation relationship database).  This will be live with the next portal release.

Still working on the sending email to the project after 3 weeks of mailing the bugs list.

gO&apos;</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1152408</commentid>
    <comment_count>11</comment_count>
    <who name="Gabe O&apos;Brien">gabe.obrien</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-07 17:06:26 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>When a bug has be idle for over 3 weeks (no comments no change in state) the project (for awaiting_commiter) or the mailing list (awaiting_project) will be emailed instead of the ipzilla bug.

This has been fixed in code and will be live with the next rollout of the portal.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1165058</commentid>
    <comment_count>12</comment_count>
    <who name="Gabe O&apos;Brien">gabe.obrien</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-26 17:24:02 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Closing because it is done.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1216619</commentid>
    <comment_count>13</comment_count>
    <who name="Bjorn Freeman-Benson">bjorn.freeman-benson</who>
    <bug_when>2008-04-28 18:06:08 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Verified. Closing.</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>