<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.1"
          urlbase="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/"
          
          maintainer="webmaster@eclipse.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>214931</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-10 13:18:00 -0500</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>An &quot;ssh&quot; window pops up for every operation with the JavaHL connector</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-02-07 09:57:17 -0500</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>5</classification_id>
          <classification>Technology</classification>
          <product>Subversive</product>
          <component>Connectors</component>
          <version>unspecified</version>
          <rep_platform>PC</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows XP</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>normal</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Martin Oberhuber">martin.oberhuber</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Alexander Gurov">alexander.gurov</assigned_to>
          
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1129074</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Martin Oberhuber">martin.oberhuber</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-10 13:18:20 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>When I enable the JavaHL connector, a black DOS-Prompt-like window with title &quot;SSH&quot; pops up on every operation. 

That&apos;s ugly, and also it seems to show that separate ssh sessions are created for each and every operation. That&apos;s slow when sitting in a remote location. It would be better to have a single ssh session and re-use that one for multiple commands.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1129075</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Martin Oberhuber">martin.oberhuber</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-10 13:20:21 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Also, the native cygwin/ssh.exe program does not use the information about my SSH home directory so it does not find my private keys and asks for a password on each and every invocation.

The Preferences from Eclipse General &gt; Network Connections &gt; SSH2 should be used.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1151746</commentid>
    <comment_count>2</comment_count>
    <who name="Alexander Gurov">alexander.gurov</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-07 04:39:47 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>The native JavaHL library does not have built-in support of SSH protocol. So, it use external tool in order to work through this protocol.
You can avoid this &quot;DOS-like&quot; windows by using SVN Kit client which provides built-in support of SSH protocol. Also SVN Kit reuses existing sessions. So, it can work faster than JavaHL with SSH protocol in some cases.
If you use SVN 1.5 compatible connector, please note that JavaHL 1.5.0 at this moment much more stable that SVN Kit 1.2.0 which also supports SVN 1.5.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1151747</commentid>
    <comment_count>3</comment_count>
    <who name="Alexander Gurov">alexander.gurov</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-07 04:41:03 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>P.S.
When SVN Kit is used SSH settings could be defined in the Repository Location properties.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1151874</commentid>
    <comment_count>4</comment_count>
    <who name="Martin Oberhuber">martin.oberhuber</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-07 09:00:19 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>Well other windows clients just come with their own compiled ssh.exe version to avoid the very problem of DOS-windows popping up: TortoiseSVN, for instance, ships with TortoisePlink.exe, a variant of PuTTY&apos;s plink that&apos;s compiled with /subsystem:windows to avoid the DOS prompt.

I had thought that Subversive could do the same.

Given that JavaHL is deemed more stable and mature than SVNKit I had hoped that one can get it to work properly -- currently I find it unusable on windows such that I&apos;d prefer not having it at all on windows since it just caused confusion for me.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1151885</commentid>
    <comment_count>5</comment_count>
    <who name="Alexander Gurov">alexander.gurov</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-07 09:24:19 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>You can use in the Windows environment the same executable (TortoisePlink.exe) as described here: http://www.woodwardweb.com/java/000155.html

This will remove &quot;DOS-like&quot; window for JavaHL, but you still prompted for password each time when accessing repository. So, regarding to this I preffer to use SVN Kit in order to access SSH repositories from the Windows environment.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1151941</commentid>
    <comment_count>6</comment_count>
    <who name="Martin Oberhuber">martin.oberhuber</who>
    <bug_when>2008-02-07 09:57:17 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>PLink can also made to run without password, either via PuTTY&apos;s pageant program or via private key without passphrase:

http://tortoisesvn.net/ssh_howto
http://tortoisesvn.net/node/35
http://www.tortoisecvs.org/ssh.shtml

It would be helpful if the Subversive JavaHL client supported changing the ssh executable to use, and provided docs similar to the ones mentioned.</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>