<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.1"
          urlbase="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/"
          
          maintainer="webmaster@eclipse.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>214915</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-10 11:16:00 -0500</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>Concrete context model</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2008-03-25 11:45:51 -0400</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>8</classification_id>
          <classification>WebTools</classification>
          <product>Dali JPA Tools</product>
          <component>Framework</component>
          <version>2.0</version>
          <rep_platform>PC</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows XP</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>FIXED</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>2.0 M6</target_milestone>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Neil Hauge">neil.hauge</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Neil Hauge">neil.hauge</assigned_to>
          
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1128960</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Neil Hauge">neil.hauge</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-10 11:16:27 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>A concrete context model is needed to solve some of our current model problems such as lack of extensibility and expandability, and complexity/maintainability.

This will require a large refactoring that will affect both the model and UI code.  The current Dali model will be broken into two distinct models, one being the resource model and one being the context model.  

The resource model will be responsible for modeling and managing the physical XML and Java JPA artifacts.  The XML resource model will use the EMF XML Translators to read and write the XML artifacts.  The Java Resource model will use the Dali Annotation Framework to read and write Java annotations via the AST.  This separate resource model is necessary primarily due to the limitations of the EMF XML Translation framework, which can compromise an object model depending on the physical XML structure that it manages. 

The context model will represent the JPA meta-data, abstracted from the physical file and file management constraints mentioned above. There will be an XML context model and a Java context model which implement common interfaces.  The UI will need to be updated to use these interfaces where they have changed.  Since we are also removing EMF from the Context model, the UI will need to be changed to use a different update mechanism.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1183394</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Neil Hauge">neil.hauge</who>
    <bug_when>2008-03-25 11:45:51 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Marking as fixed as this code base is now a part of M6.</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>