<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<!DOCTYPE bugzilla SYSTEM "https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/page.cgi?id=bugzilla.dtd">

<bugzilla version="4.4.1"
          urlbase="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/"
          
          maintainer="webmaster@eclipse.org"
>

    <bug>
          <bug_id>214975</bug_id>
          
          <creation_ts>2008-01-10 18:41:00 -0500</creation_ts>
          <short_desc>[Trim] Double click on view icon in trim could restore with focus</short_desc>
          <delta_ts>2013-06-06 14:55:22 -0400</delta_ts>
          <reporter_accessible>1</reporter_accessible>
          <cclist_accessible>1</cclist_accessible>
          <classification_id>2</classification_id>
          <classification>Eclipse</classification>
          <product>Platform</product>
          <component>UI</component>
          <version>3.4</version>
          <rep_platform>PC</rep_platform>
          <op_sys>Windows Vista</op_sys>
          <bug_status>RESOLVED</bug_status>
          <resolution>WONTFIX</resolution>
          
          
          <bug_file_loc></bug_file_loc>
          <status_whiteboard></status_whiteboard>
          <keywords></keywords>
          <priority>P3</priority>
          <bug_severity>enhancement</bug_severity>
          <target_milestone>---</target_milestone>
          
          
          <everconfirmed>1</everconfirmed>
          <reporter name="Kevin McGuire">Kevin_McGuire</reporter>
          <assigned_to name="Eric Moffatt">emoffatt</assigned_to>
          
          
          <votes>0</votes>

      

      

      

          <comment_sort_order>oldest_to_newest</comment_sort_order>  
          <long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1129372</commentid>
    <comment_count>0</comment_count>
    <who name="Kevin McGuire">Kevin_McGuire</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-10 18:41:13 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>I had a case where I knew that I had the CVS Repo View open in my explorer stack, which happened to be minimized.  So I went to the view in the trim (which I recognized because of the icon) and wanted to use the view but not in a fast view fashion (because I knew there were a number of things I wanted to do).

There isn&apos;t a direct way to do that. Of course you can restore the stack via the restore icon, but what I really wanted was &quot;please let me use this view but not as a fast view anymore).  It occurred to me that the gesture which I might expect to accomplish this would be to double click on the view icon in the trim stack.  The logic being &quot;click means use as fast view&quot; so double click should do something related.  In fact I tried it on the hope it did actually do that :)</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1129646</commentid>
    <comment_count>1</comment_count>
    <who name="Eric Moffatt">emoffatt</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-11 10:05:53 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>
Kevin, I&apos;m unsure why we&apos;d want to provide this. The only way to show the view as a non-fast view is to restore the whole stack (for which we already have an affordance), do we really want two ways to do the same thing? 
</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1129783</commentid>
    <comment_count>2</comment_count>
    <who name="Kevin McGuire">Kevin_McGuire</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-11 12:15:36 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>What I discovered was that I (a user) wasn&apos;t thinking about restoring the stack, I was thinking about it in terms of workflow around the view itself. Yet our affordance is around stack management. OK that&apos;stechnically correct, but surprisingly for me wasn&apos;t my mental model at that moment: I wanted to do something with the view, but having to manage the stack felt like an indirection and mechanical requirement of the UI.

That said, in truth I&apos;m not sure its a good suggestion (hence the &quot;could&quot; not &quot;should&quot; in the title &lt;g&gt;).  The fact though that I, a person who was part of the design discussions for this, had a moment of indecision, seemed worth recording.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1129889</commentid>
    <comment_count>3</comment_count>
    <who name="Eric Moffatt">emoffatt</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-11 15:03:41 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>
Fair enough...your call. If you convince yourself it&apos;s a good idea I&apos;ll buy it...;-).
</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1129937</commentid>
    <comment_count>4</comment_count>
    <who name="Eric Moffatt">emoffatt</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-11 15:47:23 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>
Hmmm, it turns out that this may be a non-issue (for now) due to technical reasons (double-click isn&apos;t &apos;natively&apos; handled for ToolItems).

That being said we should leave this open since, as we just went over, we -can- double click on a view in a non-minimized stack (to maximize) so it&apos;s not a far stretch to think that double clicking on a minimized view should do something &apos;similar&apos;...
</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>1130612</commentid>
    <comment_count>5</comment_count>
    <who name="Eric Moffatt">emoffatt</who>
    <bug_when>2008-01-14 09:39:32 -0500</bug_when>
    <thetext>
We should see where this fits with whatever enhancements we make to the screen real-estate management in 4.0.
</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>2268577</commentid>
    <comment_count>6</comment_count>
    <who name="Dani Megert">daniel_megert</who>
    <bug_when>2013-06-05 10:41:33 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>Removing outdated target milestone.</thetext>
  </long_desc><long_desc isprivate="0" >
    <commentid>2269471</commentid>
    <comment_count>7</comment_count>
    <who name="Eric Moffatt">emoffatt</who>
    <bug_when>2013-06-06 14:55:22 -0400</bug_when>
    <thetext>
I always thought this was a bad idea...</thetext>
  </long_desc>
      
      

    </bug>

</bugzilla>